john uh
as we're you know it's great hearing
this
tiered um release
um or staggered releases it was called
and knowing again was as you just
brought up what the tactics you know
does nsa and the cia with the tax would
be you know when pancreatic becomes
this bigger thing that
they'll take notice of once it's a
threat that they can't they can't
disrupt it in the traditional ways
how do you see this potentially changing
just the landscape of freedom of speech
because we're in a country now that is
not a democracy if you're shutting down
rt right
it's not a democracy i mean that's what
so then they should be able to if you
don't like what they're saying well then
are we gonna shut down fox news next i
don't like i don't i don't agree with
fox news i don't agree with msnbc do we
shut them down i mean
so uh because you know like i said i've
been i've been demonetized for 15 months
now and yeah i'm a comedian in my in an
apartment you know what i mean talking
about uh
you know what's wrong with this country
and i ha and i'm a threat i'm a threat
i'm a comedian who who talks about
surfing and batman is also a threat like
this is just maddening to me so how do
you see yeah this is why the prosecution
of julian assange is so dangerous that
this exactly is the reason why
julian's
case is such a slippery slope
because you use the uh the espionage act
to prosecute a journalist and even if
you don't believe that he's a journalist
which i do
you can't deny that he's a publisher
and so
if he's convicted under the espionage
act
then what's to keep the washington post
national security reporter from being
convicted or the wall street journal the
new york times
whoever in the white house happens to be
in the white house if he doesn't like
something that's been written
and there's one little kernel of
information that you know
may or may not be legitimately
classified what's to keep the white
house from going after that next person
so we're we're all in danger you're
you're exactly right graham that
we're not in a democracy
if we were in a democracy we as adults
would be able to choose
the sources
of news that we want to consume
and we just simply can't do that
i can't go anymore to press tv
to get the iranian side of a story or to
telesur or to rt america i can't even go
to al jazeera america it doesn't even
exist anymore
so this is something that is going to
i think open a a path
that
had been closed or has been closed uh to
us
uh this is this is
mccarthyism
all over again i hate speaking in
hyperbole but i really don't believe
this is hyperbole it's dangerous
you know this is another thing and
forgive me for getting on a soapbox but
when i was um when i was assigned to the
state department for a few years i was
the human rights officer and i had to i
had to write the human rights report
every year for the country that i was
assigned to i was in bahrain and uh and
send it to congress and i used to say
you know we we profess to be this
shining beacon of hope
for democracy and civil rights and human
rights and civil liberties and it's
you know what what would a host country
think for example
when
john kiriakou the human rights guy goes
into the minister of interior's office
and says your excellency i have to warn
you
your
your men beat this 15 year old boy to
death the other day because he marched
in a pro-democracy demonstration that is
illegal it's an extra
judicial killing and i'm going to put it
in the human rights report
and then 15 minutes later the cia
station chief walks in and says
don't listen to the human rights guy
we want you to open a secret prison here
where we can bring people to be tortured
don't tell anybody and we're gonna give
you 50 million dollars to cover the
costs and grease the right palms
well it's the same thing with
information
we say one thing and then we do the
completely opposite thing
this is an antidote to that
it's an antidote because it's based
overseas it is utterly and completely
transparent
and will pro will protect the system
the system will protect itself
so people really can
have a free exchange of ideas something
that just simply doesn't exist on
twitter on facebook on youtube or on any
of these other uh platforms not anymore
and something i just want to make sure i
add there too you know we talk about the
espionage act right and how atrocious it
is that's being used in this way look um
julian's not an american citizen right
right
this is more dangerous it's unreal right
so it just goes to show the danger of
you know real power in these situations
um
we at pan quake we not only understand
these kinds of things but we take our
role seriously as an international
presence right we're not going to be
doing the bidding of some government
based upon some government thing right
we really want to have an information
system that has free flow of information
all over the world between in anybody
who wants to connect to anybody else
using our network and that's the thing
that really
is sacrosanct about the model we're
trying to build um
you know so i i founded something called
privacy lab at yale that's part of
something called the information society
project it's called that because we have
an information society right um and we
need to take seriously the role of free
flow of information and how vital that
is to a democracy if we're going to have
a democracy but also if we're just going
to have normal conversations between you
know uh as friends as family without
this intense polarization and animosity
that's been brewing um all of that
manipulation
all of that that's happened has a lot to
do with the locking down of the
information system some of that is for
private data brokers who want to spy on
us and ostensibly sell us things right
some of that is from these you know uh
government spies and agencies which are
working in tandem with the private you
know um entities and some of that are
folks who are very powerful who are
trying to push propaganda push control
of populations shut down movements shut
down activists shut down anybody who has
an impact that goes against their you
know plans and schemes and um
you know
the role that something like
pancreatic.com can play in opening up
that information system can't be you
know uh uh
overstated um it is uh absolutely
incredible what can happen when we are
allowed to speak to each other when we
are allowed to make our own decisions
based upon varying information instead
of being sold some lines and propaganda
so
how much do you think as we wrap up here
because i know you guys got to go i know
you've been doing interviews all day and
i appreciate your time um
how how much is the the like the bitcoin
white paper did it influence the uh
formulation of pan quake
that's a general question sure so um
i i love that you say we don't have that
much time left and then give me that no
and then give me this this massive like
there's no way to answer this question
in less than 10 minutes but
it's fine we're not pressed for time i'm
just respecting i know you guys are busy
but those are all you want to answer
so what blockchain technology represents
is a really clever way right of
verifying information reaching consensus
so that you can have machines talk to
each other without central authority
right um so in the sense where bitcoin
does accomplish that although a lot of
it of course has been centralized in
exchanges and so on and so forth but in
the sense where it does accomplish that
that's similar to what we're trying to
do um with pancake now we care about
free flow of information and content and
so on so we have a content
based blockchain right um but we can
have nodes in the network reach
consensus and verify that hey you know
john sent a quake quake is what we're
calling our short messages um and
be able to say hey this belongs on the
blockchain john's a verified you know
pancake user and then commit that to the
blockchain record that blockchain is
basically a ledger or spreadsheet
however you want to think of it
that can then be shared and broadcast
around the world to all these other
machines on the network um
unlike the model where you know you have
a big tech company that has some
database somewhere in some unknown
location and they can just tweak and
modify and change it and literally
rewriting history right which we see or
ban somebody and just everything goes
poof right um unless it's been archived
and so on and so forth
but something else i should bring up i
guess just real quickly we take very
seriously um you know the archiving of
information as well um we want to solve
in some way the thing that's called bit
rot right we want to make sure that
people can not only share information
but that the information that they're
sharing on pan quake will be resilient
to um censorship itself and we have some
clever things we're working on from that
standpoint too um we want to make sure
if you share an article from something
like al jazeera english or or some other
thing that's being blocked banned or
disappears um that there's some
permanence of the information you're
sharing in our network too um so we're
working on that
all right
well i mean this is uh i really
appreciate your time and where can
people go to support this
uh pancreatic.com donate um you also can
go pancreatic.com crypto to donate
cryptocurrency um we also have a sub
stack uh talk liberation um which is not
paywall but if you do subscribe your
money for subscribing five dollars a
month um goes towards uh the pan quake
build all of that money um those are the
ways you can support us but the other
thing is we need you as regular people
to be our media so far that's how we
succeeded and if you can help amplify us
talk about us um share some of our
videos um share this stream please you
know um that's the way that we're to win
that's the way that we're going to get
there so
amen right on thank you for thank you
especially you know
for doing this taking the time and
especially in light of what just
happened with the julian ruling it's
it's like like john said it's important
now more than ever so
um
i appreciate it thank you so much john
kerry
thanks a lot
have a great day you too
hey everybody thanks for watching we are
still in our like ninth month of
demonetization from youtube so support
what we're doing at patreon.com
gramelwood or rockfin.com graham ellwood
which is a blockchain cryptocurrency
platform
it's free to sign up and there's a
premium level at ten dollars a month and
for that you get everybody on the
platform's premium content myself lee
camp ron plecon jimmy dore whitney webb
kim iverson abby martin and many many
others you can also support what we're
doing at venmo at graham
and go to grahamelwood.com we have a
paypal button and a p.o box i also have
crypto wallets which are all in the show
notes thanks for supporting what we do
you